今日はやけに目が疼く
My eyes are throbbing with pain
more than usual today.
侵入者
Intruders?
A small and weak female voice.
地下に閉じ込める気だ
They intend to trap her underground.
ダメだ
They mustn't.
四龍の戦士よ
Warriors of the four dragons...
なんだ
What is this?
これより お前達は我々の分身
You are now our other halves.
緋龍を主とし 命の限り これを守り
これを愛し 決して裏切るな
You will serve Hiryuu as your master, protecting him with your lives.
You will love him and never betray him.
なんだ この声は
What is this voice?
目が疼く
My eyes are throbbing.
あの少女に触れた時 声が響いて
The moment I touched that girl,
a voice echoed through my head.
その場に崩れ落ちてしまいそうになった
I nearly collapsed where I stood.
白い龍が居た
There was a white dragon.
どうして俺は 彼を白い龍だと思ってあんだろう
Why did I think he was a white dragon?
どうしてこんなに...
Why does it feel...
血が炊けるように熱い
like my blood is boiling?
My eyes are throbbing.
目が疼く
Be still.
静まれ
この力はもう二度と知られてはならないのだから
No one must learn of this power again.
Episode 13:      Echoing Fear
A villager nearly took you below ground?!
里の人間に地下に連れて行かれそうになった
Yeah.
RUMBLE
おのれ
Damn them.
Not only do they refuse to respect you,
but they tried to trap you underground!
オノレ 姫様を敬わぬばかりか 地下に閉じ込めるなど
余程 私の逆鱗に触れたいらしいな
They must be determined to incur my wrath!
Ki-ja, your face!
キジャ 顔が
落ち着け
Calm down.
You're such a sheltered kid.
まったく坊ちゃん育ちは 一般人殺す気が
You want to kill common villagers? Grow up.
大人になれよ
You should grow up yourself, former general.
あんたもな 元将軍
But you're sure that man was the Blue Dragon?
けど さっきの彼奴が青龍だなんて 間違いないの
Yes.
だったらなんで逃げたんだ
Then why did he run away?
分からぬ
I don't know.
The Blue Dragon, the villagers...
青龍といい 里人といい
どうなっているのだここは
What's going on with this place?
同じ龍の里でも 白龍の里とは真逆ってことだね
They're both dragon villages,
but this one's the polar opposite of the White Dragon's village.
なに
What?
白龍の里を見てきたからここは異質に見えるけど
Because we saw the White Dragon's village first,
this village seems different.
考えてみたら 白龍の里が特別なのかも
But now that I think about it, maybe the White Dragon's village was the exception.
ここでは赤い髪への信仰はないし
These villagers don't revere red hair,
龍神の力を崇高なものともしていない
and they don't regard the dragon's power as exalted.
それどころか 忌まわしく思ってそうな節だってある
In fact, I get the feeling
they find it abominable.
村人にはもちろん
Not just the villagers, but the Blue Dragon himself,
may see us merely as intruders.
青龍にとっても俺等は本当に侵入者でしかないのかも
ばかな
That's ridiculous!
The four dragon warriors must hasten to join their master immediately.
四龍たるもの 主の元に一刻も早くはせ参じるものだ
Once I met the princess, I didn't hesitate,
up to and including the moment I left my village.
私は姫様に会って 里を出るまで
何も躊躇う事はなかったぞ
You don't hesitate enough.
あんたは迷いなさすぎ
当然
Of course not.
That wasn't a compliment.
いや 褒めてはいない
But he saved me.
でも 助けてくれたよ
The Blue Dragon had gentle hands.
青龍 優しい手をしていた
I want to speak with him.
会って話してたい
So you're going back into that maze?
つまりまた あの迷路に入るの
Yes.
怖い目にあったのに 全然怯まないのな
Even after that scary ordeal,
you're not fazed at all.
根性あるじゃん お姫様
You have guts, Princess.
行こう
Let's go.
あの行き止まりの場所になにかあるんだよね
There was something at that dead end, right?
姫さんはここにいろ
You stay here, Princess.
ハク
Hak?
Yun and I will find the Blue Dragon.
青龍は俺とユンで首根っこ引っ掴んでくるから
What are you saying? I'll go.
なにを言う 行くなら私だろう
Okay. We're counting on you, White Snake.
よし 任せた白蛇様
What?!
なに
In any case, don't go back in there, Princess.
とにかく 姫さんは もう中に入るな
外で待って
Wait outside and-
No.
いいえ
行くのは私とキジャよユン
Ki-ja, Yun, and I will go.
ハクはここで待ってて
You wait here, Hak.
キジャは青龍の場所がユンは道が分かる
Ki-ja can sense the Blue Dragon, and Yun's good with directions.
And I must meet the Blue Dragon.
そして 私が青龍に会わなきゃ
I believe I must do that myself.
それは 私の役目だと思うの
お願い
Please.
で だれかが外で里人を見張ってなきゃいけない
Well, someone has to stay outside and watch for the villagers.
それが余った俺ってわけですか
I'm the only one left, so I have to do it?
ハクだから任せるの
Because I know I can depend on you.
I'll be careful not to let anything
like that happen again.
さっきみたいな事にならないよう気を付けるから
ハク
Hak?
今度はちゃんと戻ってくださいよ
This time, come back.
でないと この先 うぜぇくらい側から離れませんからね
Otherwise, I'll stick annoyingly
close to you from now on.
ハク
Hak...
I avoid annoying things.
うざいのは嫌だ
だから気を付ける
So I'll be careful.
Yes, please do.
お そうして下さいよ
I pity him.
不愍
Hey, White Snake.
おい 白蛇
I'm not a white-
白蛇ではなっ...
頼む
I'm counting on you.
言われずとも
Goes without saying.
見てる
They're watching.
ずっと監視してやがる
They've been observing us this whole time.
What a creepy bunch.
気味悪い連中だな
ま せいぜい威嚇してやるさ
I'll just have to intimidate them.
Princess, you're actually a bit scared
without the Thunder Beast, aren't you?
お姫様 本当は少し怖いでしょう
雷獣が居ないから
Yun, don't say that!
ユン言わないで
ハクが居ると 当たり前のように便り過ぎちゃうもの
When Hak's around, I rely on him too much.
頼られたいんじゃないの 雷獣は
Doesn't the Thunder Beast
want you to rely on him?
Yes, but Hak actually served
my late father, not me.
でも ハクは本当は私ではなく父上に仕えていたの
He's still following my father's orders.
今も父上の命令を守ってくれているのよ
I don't think that's the only reason.
それだけじゅあないと思うけど
Hak didn't like being a general or a bodyguard.
ハク 将軍とか護衛とか嫌がってたし
今はまだできないけど いつかは
ハクに自由を返したいと思う
I can't do it yet,
but someday, I'd like to set Hak free.
え ここの行き止まりに隠し通路
Huh? The dead end has a hidden passage?
Yes.
It's opening!
開いた開いた
How interesting!
面白い
キジャ 行くよ
Ki-ja, let's go.
どうしたの
What's wrong?
Ah, nothing.
あっ いえ
青龍はその先に居ます
The Blue Dragon is in there.
私はここで待っていますから
I'll wait out here.
お二人で行ってください
You two go ahead.
Huh? Why?
どうして
大丈夫
It's all right.
This handsome genius knows the way.
この天才美少年が道なら把握してるから
頼んだぞ
I'll depend on you.
Got it.
了解
さて
Now, then...
この狭き様な場所で何用だ
What do you want to do in this narrow space?
We cannot allow those who follow that path to leave.
その先へ行った者は帰すわけにはゆかない
黙れ
Quiet.
赤き龍の尊さをも忘れた不届き者とも
You are scoundrels who have forgotten the Red Dragon's nobility.
あのお方に近づく事 この白龍が許さぬ
I, the White Dragon, will not
allow you to approach her.
The White Dragon is nearby.
白い龍が近くに居る
Someone is walking through the passage.
誰か通路を渡っている
アオ 隠れて
Ao, hide.
Chomp
侵入者
Intruders?
敵ならば 倒す
I will defeat any enemies!
こんにちは
Hello.
なんだ
What is this?
此奴はなんなんだ
Who is this person?
やばいよ姫様
This isn't good, Princess!
こんな穴倉の奥で面付けて蹲ってるなんて
A masked man crouching at the back of a hole like this must be dangerous!
やっぱ危ない人だったんだよ
It's you again.
まだあった
Huh?
なにこの頬袋ぱんぱんの小動物
What's this little creature with swollen cheeks?
詰め込み過ぎたよ
He's stuffed too much in there!
この子何て言う名前
What's his name?
アオ
Ao.
答えてくれるんだ
He answers questions?
That name doesn't suit him at all.
全然似合わないわね
Try to meet him halfway, Princess!
歩み寄ろうよお姫様
似合わない
It doesn't suit him.
やっぱり
I knew it.
俺も そう思う
I agree.
私はヨナ あなたの名前は
I'm Yona. What's your name?
青...龍
The Blue Dragon.
あなたの名前よ
No, your name.
それは あなた自身の名ではないでしょう
That isn't your name, is it?
I don't have a name.
名はない
ただ 青龍だ
I'm just the Blue Dragon.
Stay back!
寄るな
お前達はなんだ
Who are you people?
なぜ この里に入ってくる
Why have you entered this village?
なぜ俺に近づく なぜあの白い龍は...
Why are you approaching me?
Why is the White Dragon...
私はあなたに会う為にここまで来たの
I came here to see you.
なぜ 俺はこんなにも...
Why do I feel so strongly...
青龍 あなたの力を借りたいの
Blue Dragon, I'd like you to lend me your power.
私と一緒に来てほしい
I want you to come with me.
この少女に会いたかったと思うのだろう
...that I've wanted to meet this girl?
俺の...力
My power...
お姫様
Princess!
敵
An enemy.
青龍の力を欲する者は 敵
Those who desire the power of the Blue Dragon are enemies!
四龍の戦士達よ
Warriors of the four dragons...
お前達は我々の分身
You are now our other halves.
お前...
You...
Who are you?
お前はなんだ
なぜ 手が震える
Why are my hands trembling?
I don't know you.
お前なんか知らない
どうして
Why?
泣きたいのだろう
Why do I want to cry?
青龍 私は貴方の敵じゃないよ
Blue Dragon, I am not your enemy.
私は私と仲間が生きてゆく為に 四龍探しをしているの
I am searching for the four dragons, so that my friends and I may live.
貴方を仲間として迎えたい
I want you to become my ally.
Ally...
なか...ま
仲間
Ally.
俺は呪われているから
I am cursed.
呪われて
Cursed?
この力は決して外に知られてはならない
The outside world must never learn of this power.
破滅の力
This power of destruction.
Who told you that?
誰がそんな事を
事実だ
It's the truth.
Nod Nod
だから 行かないと
That's why you won't go?
Nod Nod
Snooze
どうしても
No matter what?
去れ
Leave.
Leave!
去れ
お姫様
Princess...
一つ言わせて
Let me say one thing.
貴方の手はとても暖かかった
Your hand was very warm.
呪いがどんなものかは知らない
I don't know anything about your curse.
でも あれが呪われた者の手だというなら
But if that was the hand of a cursed man,
貴方が恐ろしい呪いを持っていたって 私は全然構わない
then I don't care, even if you do
bear a horrific curse.
She's leaving.
行ってしまう
心臓が引きちぎられるようだ
It feels as if my heart is being torn apart.
I want you to become my ally.
貴方を仲間として迎えたい
Ally...
仲間
アオ
Ao... I want friends.
友達...欲しい
そんな事 ずっと忘れていたのに
For years... I had managed to avoid
thinking about that.
お姫様
Princess...
You look really displeased.
すっげ腑に落ちないって顔してるよ
あの部屋 何もなかった
There was nothing in that room.
彼はちゃんと食べているのかしら
Is he getting enough to eat?
何だか 大切な人を暗い檻に置き去りにした気分
I feel like I've left someone
very precious in a dark cage.
変ね 初めて会ったのに
It's strange. That was our
first meeting, and yet...
Get back!
下がる
キジャ
Ki-ja.
They're back.
出てきた
出てきたぞ
They came back.
片づけろ
Finish them.
姫様 おさがりください
Princess, stay back.
やっぱりね
I knew it.
彼等は青龍を隠す為 我々を消すつもりです
They intend to eliminate us,
to keep the Blue Dragon hidden.
消す どうして
Eliminate us? Why?
Now that you know about him,
we can't let you leave here alive!
彼奴の事を知られたからには
生きて帰すわけにはいかんのだ
Why? Why do you hide the Blue Dragon?
なぜ なぜ彼を 青龍の事を隠そうとするの
確かにここは我らの里と真逆なのかもしれません
Perhaps this place really is the opposite of my village.
尊き龍の力を呪いなどと
They called the noble dragon's power a curse.
Quiet!
だまれ
Don't fight in this narrow space!
止してよ こんな狭い所で
キジャ
Ki-ja!
ご安心を 素人相手に力は使っていません
Don't worry. I won't use
my power against amateurs!
You only punched him with tens of times the strength of most men.
常人の何十倍の力で拳骨しとるがな
お願い 教えて
Please tell me.
どうして青龍が疎まなければならないの
Why does the Blue Dragon have to be shunned?
呪いって 一体なんなの
What is this curse?
Quiet!
黙れ
地震
An earthquake?!
Run!
逃げろ
Princess!
姫様
ハク
Hak!
An earthquake?
地震
Help!
助けて
Princess!
姫さん
The princess and the others are in there.
おの奥には 姫さん達が
クソ
Damn it!
You can't be serious.
嘘...だろ
姫さん
Princess...
Princess!
姫さん
Yun! White Snake!
ユン 白蛇
I'll be careful not to let anything
like that happen again.
さっき見たいな事にならない様に気をづけるから
I shouldn't have let her go.
行かせるんじゃなかった
こう言う事態をどうして予測出来ない
Why didn't I anticipate this?
こんな所で 守れねぇって
I can't believe I failed to protect her here.
頼む イル陛下
Please, King Il...
Don't take her from me.
連れていかないでくれ
ハク
Hak...
怖いよ 本当はすごく
I'm actually really scared.
I wanted to do my best without you...
ハクが居なくても頑張ろうって思ったのに
怖くて ついハクを探してしまう
but I end up looking to you out of fear.
I'm so weak.
私はこんなにも弱い
I don't want to fail, but I...
負けたくないのに
Princess... Princess...
姫様 姫様
姫様
Princess!
キジャ
Ki-ja?
大丈夫ですか
Are you all right?
あれ どうなったの
Huh? What happened?
地震は収まったのですが
The earthquake subsided, but...
It's no use!
ダメだ
出口が塞がれてる
The exit is blocked!
No...
そんな
You can't be serious!
嘘だろう
Are we going to die?
俺等死ぬのか
We can't get out?
出られない
You must be joking!
冗談じゃない
We're trapped.
閉じ込められた
Yun?
ユン
We won't be able to breathe
for long in this small space.
こんな狭い所で息が続かないよ
I don't want to die! Help me!
死にたくない 助けてくれ
No. At this rate...
そんな このままじゃ
I'm scared, Hak.
怖い...ハク
だからなぜ其方に言われねばならんのだ
I don't need you to tell me that!
キジャ
Ki-ja?
Oh, forgive me.
申し訳ありません
For some reason, that rude man suddenly...
今なぜ唐突にあの無礼な男が頼むと頭の中で喋ったので
I'm counting on you.
...just spoke inside my head.
It made me very angry.
なんだかとてもむかむかしてしまい
姫様をお守りするのは私のお役目なのに
It's my job to protect you, Princess.
何か元気出てきたわ
I'm feeling better.
So am I!
私も元気です
大丈夫 ユン
It's okay, Yun.
必ず助けがきてくれる
Help will come for us.
待ってろ 姫さん
You just wait, Princess.
I'll...
必ず
We don't need to wait for help.
助けなど待ったずとも
この私が居る限り 案ずる事は何もございません
As long as you have me, you've nothing to fear.
K-Ki-ja, what are you going
to do with those claws?
キ キジャ どうすんのさ 爪なんか出して
Dig!
掘る
Monster!
化け物
騒がしいぞ
Don't be so noisy.
青龍の里を守る者達が情けない
The guardians of the Blue Dragon's
village are pathetic.
I told you that I am the White Dragon.
私は白龍だと言ったであろう
Th-The White Dragon!
は 白龍
There really are other dragons
that possess cursed powers!
本当にいたのか
青龍様以外にも呪いの力を持った龍が
I've had enough!
もう嫌だ
It's him. It's his fault.
彼奴が 彼奴のせいだ
彼奴が居るから 俺達はこんな
We're stuck in this hole because of him.
Let me out! Let me out!
出して 出してくれ
Why? Why is the Blue Dragon's power a curse?
どうして どうして青龍の力が呪いなの
あんなに あんなに優しい手をしてるのに
But... But his hands are so gentle.
知らぬのだ 奴の邪悪さを
You don't know how evil he can be.
He isn't evil-
彼は邪悪じゃ...
Outsiders wouldn't understand!
余所者に何が分かる
ずっと 一族の中から龍の目を持つ化け物が生まれ
For generations, monsters with the dragon's eyes have been born in our village.
青龍の力に怯えて暮らし
We live in fear of the Blue Dragon's power.
Even if the Blue Dragon dies, someone else's child becomes the new Blue Dragon.
青龍が死んでもまた誰かの子供が青龍になって
次は我が子かもしれないと
You don't know how it feels to live in fear
that your own child will be next!
死ぬまで怯えて生きる気持ちが
我々はそんな呪いを抱えていると
決して外に広めてはならないのだ
Those of us who bear that curse
must never leave the village.
A mask is placed on the Blue Dragon
as soon as he's born,
青龍は生まれてすぐ面をつけ
あまり外にも出さない
and we rarely let him outside.
それが掟だ
Those are our rules.
But the Blue Dragon used his cursed power to kill many soldiers
それなのに
青龍はその恐ろしい呪い力を使い
兵士を大勢殺したのだ
まだほんの幼い頃に
when he was only a child.
それから我々は兵が来るのを恐れ
ここに移り住んだ
We feared more soldiers would come,
so we moved here.
I can't take it anymore!
もう耐えられない
これが呪いでなくて何だ
What is this, if not a curse?!
来た
He's here.
B-Blue Dragon...
青龍...様
俺は何も...
I didn't tell the outsiders anything.
余所者に話してなんか
Stay back!
寄るな
呪いがどんなものが知らない
I know nothing about his curse.
But his eyes...
しかし 彼は確かに
息も止まる程の美しい目をしていた
are breathtakingly beautiful.
Do you see
wakaru kai
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
The same obscure lyrics and background
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
I've always talked ideals
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
Like supporting others
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
I hope you don't realize too early
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
How irresponsible I was being with my words
hayasuginai you ni
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
Since my hands are warmer than others'
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
When I hold your hand
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
Next Time
本当はもう分かっていたんだ
彼女を初めて見たあの時から
In truth, I already knew from
the moment I first saw her.
次回 暁のヨナ 第十四話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 14:
Episode 14:      Light
Light.
光
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作